登陆小队有消息吗？
Anything from the landing party?
他们马上就会送来报告，舰长
They should be sending up a report momentarily, captain.
- 怎么了？ - 背扭了一下
- Something wrong? - A kink in my back.
就是这，再高点
That's it. No, a little-- A little higher, please.
推，用力推
Push, push hard.
使劲按，史波克…
Dig it in there, Mr. Sp--
谢谢，文书，好多了
Thank you, yeoman. That's sufficient.
您需要休息，舰长，恕我冒昧
You need sleep, captain. If it's not out of line to suggest--
这种话麦考伊说得够多了，文书，谢谢
I have enough of that from Dr. McCoy, yeoman. Thank you.
麦考伊大夫是对的，舰长
Dr. McCoy is correct, captain.
过去三个月星舰的历程艰辛
After what this ship has been through in the last three months,
每个船员都需要休息…
there's not a crewman aboard who is not in need of a rest...
当然，除了我
...myself excepted, of course.
把麦考伊医生的报告传送到我房间，上尉
Have Dr. McCoy's report channelled to my quarters, lieutenant.
是，舰长
Aye, aye, captain.
美，真美
Beautiful. Beautiful.
没动物，没人，没烦恼
No animals, no people, no worries.
这正是你想要的，对吗，大夫？
Just what the doctor ordered. Right, doctor?
没有比这更好的处方啦
I couldn't have prescribed better.
我们的船员都很疲惫
We are one weary ship.
你认为舰长能批准在这休整吗？
Do you think the captain will authorise a shore leave here?
这取决于我和侦查队的报告
Well, depending upon my report and that of the other scouting parties.
耳闻还是不如一见
You know, you have to see this place to believe it.
这里就像爱丽丝的仙境
It's like something out of Alice in Wonderland.
舰长一定得下来看看
The captain has to come down.
- 他会喜欢这儿 - 他需要这样的地方
- He'd like it. - He needs it.
你有你的压力，我有我的，可他肩负我俩的压力
You've got your problems, I've got mine, but he's got ours
还有他自己的，还有430名船员的压力
plus his, plus 430 other people.
你要去哪？
Where you going?
记录细胞结构
To get some cell-structure records.
草，灌木丛
A blade of grass, a bush,
树…
a tree...
花瓣
...a flower petal.
有了这些，我们就可以了解这颗星球的生态
With these we can tell the whole planet biology.
哦，我的老天爷，要迟到了
Oh, my paws and whiskers. I'll be late.
打搅了，先生，你在附近是否看见一只
Excuse me, sir. Have you seen a rather large white rabbit
穿黄马甲戴白手套的大白兔？
with a yellow weskit and white gloves hereabout?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
苏鲁！
Sulu!
什么事？
What is it?
怎么了？
What's the matter?
你看见他们了吗？
Did you see them?
看见什么？
See what?
我什么也没看见
I don't see anything.
你看到什么了，医生？
What is it, doc?
宇宙，人类最后的疆域
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的旅程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它所执行的五年任务：是为了探索陌生的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新的生命及新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向人类未知的洪荒
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际迷航
TLF字幕组荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
翻译：疯狂小骨头 sholto
校对：kmdangdangli
第一季 第15集
奇妙的休假地
舰长日志，星历3025…
Captain's log, stardate 3025...
点3
...point 3.
我们正环绕奥米克斯三角洲区域的一颗无人星球飞行
We are orbiting an uninhabited planet in the Omicron Delta region,
这颗星球和记忆中的地球极其相似
a planet remarkably like Earth, or how we remember Earth to be:
像座美丽的公园，绿意盎然，到处是鲜花，树木和绿草…
Park-like, beautiful, green. Flowers, trees, green lawns...
宁静安详
...quiet and restful.
美得让人难以置信
Almost too good to be true.
登录名单上怎么不见您的名字，长官？
Sir? I don't see your name in any of the shore parties.
我是有些疲倦，文书，可还没累趴下
Well, I may be tired, yeoman, but I'm not falling apart.
你可以走了
Dismissed.
- 是，长官 - 登录休假一分队
- Aye, aye, sir. - Shore leave party one.
原地待命
Stand by your section.
接下来将按字母顺序点名
You will be called in alphabetical order.
史波克，我们先送右舷区的船员下去
Mr. Spock, we're beaming down the starboard section first.
你想随哪一区下去？
Which section would you like to go with?
我不需要，舰长
Not necessary in my case, captain.
在我的星球上，休息便是安息，不再耗费能量的意思
On my planet, to rest is to rest: To cease using energy.
对我来说，在草地上跑来跑去是不合逻辑的
To me, it is quite illogical to run up and down on green grass,
那不是保持体力，反而是消耗体力
using energy instead of saving it.
- 我是寇克 - 收到麦考伊医生
- Kirk here. - Dr. McCoy calling
- 从星球发来的呼叫，舰长 - 好的，开启频道，乌乎拉
- from the planet, captain. - Yes, open a channel, Uhura.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长，你要下来吗？
Captain, are you beaming down?
我不打算来，怎么了，老骨头？
I hadn't planned to, Bones. Why?
嗯，要么是我们的侦察器和探测器坏了
Well, either our scouting probes and detectors are malfunctioning,
这里的美把我们这些侦察员迷得如痴如醉，疏忽大意
and all us scouts careless and beauty-intoxicated...
要么是我自己不再胜任这份工作
...or I must report myself unfit for duty.
此话怎讲
Explain.
在这颗原本无人居住的星球上…
On this supposedly uninhabited planet...
我撞见了只大兔子，从自己背心里掏出只金表
...I just saw a large rabbit pull a gold watch from his vest
还说它迟到了
and claim that he was late.
这笑话不错，老骨头，我也讲一个
That's pretty good, Bones. All right, I got one for you.
兔子后面还跟着一个金发小女孩，对吧？
The rabbit was followed by a little blond girl, right?
对，没错
As a matter of fact, yes.
他们穿过篱笆上的洞，消失了
They disappeared through a hole in a hedge.
好吧，大夫，你的报告我会考虑
All right, doctor. I’ll take your report under consideration.
通话完毕
Captain out.
那就是麦考伊的药方：哄骗中来点神秘
That's a McCoy pill: A little mystery sugarcoating.
他想让我下去，怕我拒绝
He wants to get me down there. Afraid I won't swallow it.
很好，舰长
Very well, captain.
我正要和你谈这事
Something I did come to discuss.
好的，史波克，什么事？
Yes, Mr. Spock, what is it?
这是我从麦考伊的日志中找到的
I picked this up from Dr. McCoy's log.
有位船员出现压力大和疲劳的症状
We have a crew member aboard who's showing signs of stress and fatigue.
反应速度下降了9%-12%
Reaction time down 9 to 12 percent.
相关的考评也比正常值低了三级
Associational rating, norm minus three.
这评级也太低了
That's much too low a rating.
他变得烦躁，喜欢争论
He's becoming irritable and quarrelsome,
然而他却拒绝休整
yet he refuses to take rest and rehabilitation.
尽管他有权拒绝，可我们发现…
Now, he has that right, but we found--
只要星舰安然无恙，船员便无权拒绝
A crewman's right ends where the safety of the ship begins.
我现在就命令这个人登陆休假
Now, that man will go ashore on my orders.
- 他叫什么名字？ - 詹姆士·寇克
- What's his name? - James Kirk.
祝您玩得高兴，舰长
Enjoy yourself, captain.
那是颗有趣的星球，相信您会很喜欢
It's an interesting planet. I believe you'll find it quite pleasant,
很像你们的地球
very much like your Earth.
侦察队没发现任何动物和人造物品
The scouts have detected no animals, artefacts
或任何力场
or force fields of any kind.
只有平静，阳光和清新的空气
Only peace, sunshine and good air.
什么麻烦都没有
You'll have no problems.
怎么总是和你在一起工作？
Always have to be work with you?
这里真好
There's so much loveliness.
要是舰长要的报告不及时送到…
You won't find all this so lovely if our report for the captain
可就没这么好了
isn't ready when he asks for it.
没功夫耽误了
Which shouldn't be long.
罗德里格斯，特勒，一切顺利吗？
Rodriguez. Teller. Everything all right?
是的，长官，我们已完成了标本调查
Yes, sir. We've completed the specimen survey.
很好，那就足够了
Good. That should be sufficient.
你们一弄好，就传送给史波克
Beam it up to Mr. Spock when you're ready.
开始好好享受吧
Start enjoying yourselves.
谢谢长官，长官
Thank you, sir. And, sir,
麦考伊医生和苏鲁先生在那边
I think you'll find Dr. McCoy and Mr. Sulu that way.
谢谢
Thank you.
真宁静
Restful.
经历那么多，很难相信…
After what we've been through, it's hard to believe
- 还有如此美丽的地方 - 的确很美
- a place this beautiful exists. - It is beautiful.
如此迷人
So lovely.
还很宁静
And restful.
我赞同您的观点，舰长
I mean, affirmative, captain.
麦考伊
McCoy!
在这边
Over here!
老骨头
Bones.
最近还有什么关于兔子的笑话吗？
Know any good rabbit jokes lately?
的确是有
As a matter of fact, I do,
可不是什么玩笑，瞧
but this is not one of them. Look at this.
这要么是真的，要么是我的幻觉
I saw what I saw, or maybe I hallucinated it,
但我想让你看了之后，能告诉我你的想法
but I want you to take a look at it and tell me what you think about it.
是些脚印
Footprints.
像只兔子的
Could be a rabbit.
从脚印大小看…
It would have to be an unusual creature...
它不是普通的兔子
...to make this-size tracks.
苏鲁呢？他能证实你的所见吗？
What about Mr. Sulu? Will he confirm what you saw?
不能，当时他在勘察植物
Negative. He was examining the flora at the time.
呼叫舰桥，我是舰长
Bridge, this is the captain.
- 苏鲁在哪？ - 他在收集标本
- Where is Mr. Sulu? - Collecting specimens.
- 我是舰桥 - 第一登陆队
- Bridge. - Has the first shore party
- 传送下来了吗？ - 还没，舰长
- beamed down yet? - Negative, captain.
- 正准备传送 - 通知所有人
- They're just about to start. - Get this message
原地待命，任何人不许离开星舰
to all shore parties: Stand by. No one is to leave the ship.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
就为这你就要取消登陆休假吗，吉姆？
You mean you're cancelling the shore leave on account of this, Jim?
既然你是医生，你能对此解释一下吗？
Now, you're the doctor, doctor. Can you explain this?
- 不能，可… - 我也不能
- Well, no, but-- - Neither can I.
我是说，看上去没什么危险
I mean, it looks harmless.
或许真就没危险
Probably is harmless.
但在我的人下来之前
But before I bring my people down here,
我得证实它的安全性
I want proof it's harmless.
- 你在干什么？ - 我在射击，舰长
- What do you think you're doing? - Target shooting, captain.
很赞吧？
Isn't it a beauty?
这种枪我还没收集过
Haven't got anything like this in my collection.
- 你从哪弄来的，苏鲁？ - 我找到的
- Where did you get it, Mr. Sulu? - I found it.
这种巧合很不可思议
I know it's a crazy coincidence,
但我一直就想要一把这样的枪
but I've always wanted one like this.
我发现它就躺在那
I found it lying right over there.
过去警察专用的枪…
An old-time police special...
保养得还很好
...and in beautiful condition.
这种枪正是…
Hasn't been one like this made in...
几个世纪前制造的
...oh, a couple centuries.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu.
它通过化学爆炸产生的气体推动…
It fires lead pellets propelled by expanding gases
射出铅弹
from a chemical explosion.
我来保管它，这里新鲜的空气似乎让你兴奋过头了
I'll hang onto it. The fresh air seems to have made you trigger-happy.
麦考伊大夫的兔子，长官，它一定到过这儿
Dr. McCoy's rabbit, sir. He must've gone through here.
你确定仪器没有检测到这颗星球上的动物？
Are you sure our instruments didn't show any animal life on this planet?
确定
Absolutely.
没有飞禽走兽，没有昆虫，什么都没有
No birds, no mammals, no insects, nothing.
我确定检测结果无误
I'm certain our readings weren't off.
我觉得这是个精心策划的恶作剧，可…
I'd like to believe this is an elaborate gag, but...
巴罗斯文书，你和苏鲁一起
Yeoman Barrows, you accompany Mr. Sulu.
找出这些脚印是从哪来的
Find out where those tracks came from.
医生，你和我再回到那片空地
Doctor, you come with me back to the glade.
我想再看看那里
I'd like to take another look at that area.
看来这次的登陆休假非比寻常
This is turning out to be one very unusual shore leave.
- 现在算好的了 - 为何？
- Well, it could've been worse. - How?
还好你没见到那只兔子
You could've seen the rabbit.
怎么了，老骨头，你怎么变得神经兮兮的？
What's the matter, Bones, you getting a persecution complex?
我开始觉得自己被人捉弄了
I'm beginning to feel a little bit picked on,
- 你指的是这种感觉吧？ - 这种感觉我太了解啦
- if that's what you mean. - I know the feeling well.
当时我还在学校…
I had it at the Academy.
有这么一位学长…
An upperclassman there...
总是一次又一次地捉弄我
One practical joke after another, and always on me.
他是我的梦魇，他叫芬尼根
My own personal devil. A guy by the name of Finnegan.
你是个正儿八经的学生…
And you being the very serious young cadet--
正儿八经？老实说，老骨头…
Serious? I'll make a confession, Bones.
我当时不苟言笑，这越发让芬尼根乐此不疲
I was absolutely grim, which delighted Finnegan no end.
他是那种会把一碗冷汤放到你床上的人
He was the kind of guy to put a bowl of cold soup in your bed
或者在半掩的门上放桶水
or a bucket of water propped on a half-opened door.
你永远都不知道下次他会怎么捉弄你
You never knew where he'd strike next.
这里脚印更多
More tracks.
看来你的兔子是从那来的
Looks like your rabbit came from over there.
一个女孩的脚印
A girl's footprints.
就是跟在兔子后面的金发女孩
The young blond girl I saw chasing it.
是的
Yes.
你跟着兔子
You follow the rabbit.
我去找女孩
I'll backtrack the girl.
我俩在山的另一侧汇合
I'll meet you around the other side of the hill.
好吧，本人可不太喜欢那只兔子，吉姆
Good. I got a personal grudge against that rabbit, Jim.
吉姆
Jim!
芬尼根？
Finnegan?
难以置信
I can't believe it.
你永远猜不到我会怎么捉弄你
You never know when I'm going to strike.
嗨，吉姆？
Huh, Jim?
这怎么可能？
How's this?
来呀，来呀，是我呀，芬尼根
Come on, come on. It's me, Finnegan.
还好吧，小吉米？
All right, Jimmy boy?
来吧，来打我呀，这不是你一直想要的吗？
Go ahead, lay one on me, because that's what you always wanted, isn't it?
来吧，来吧
Come on, come on.
- 来呀，来呀 - 好的
- Come on, come on. - All right,
再说一遍试试
let's try that one again.
来呀
Go.
逃呀！又找借口，小吉米
Go! Any excuse, Jim baby.
逃吧
Run away.
- 出什么事了？ - 文书巴罗斯
- What was it? - Yeoman Barrows.
怎么了？
What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的意思是，我知道，我…
I mean, I do know. I...
我一直循着脚印走，突然他就出现了
I was following the tracks, and there he was.
- 谁？ - 他
- Who was? - Him!
巴罗斯，告诉我你看见了谁
Barrows, give me your report.
他…
He...
他身穿斗篷，长官…
He had a cloak, sir, and...
拿着一把嵌着宝石的匕首
...and a dagger with jewels on it.
你确定这都是你亲眼所见？
Are you sure you're not imagining all this?
舰长，我知道这听起来不可思议，但这不是我的幻觉
Captain, I know it sounds incredible, but I did not imagine it
非但不是幻觉，他还把我…
any more than I imagined he did this.
听上去像是唐璜【情圣代名词】
Sounds like Don Juan.
是的
Yes.
这…
It was...
这就像故事书里写得一样，我一边走…
It was some sort of storybook, walking around here...
一边想…
...and I was thinking...
少女都渴望遇到…
...all a girl needs is...
唐璜
...Don Juan.
就这样幻想着
Just daydreaming,
幻想着你想见到的那个人
the way you would about someone you'd like to meet.
苏鲁刚才和你在一起，现在他人呢？
Mr. Sulu was with you. Where is he now?
他…他追他去了
He... He ran after him.
你陪着她，大夫
Stay with her, doctor.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu.
Sulu!
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu!
Sulu!
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu!
露丝？
Ruth?
露丝
Ruth.
吉姆，亲爱的…
Jim, darling...
是我呀
...it is me.
我是露丝
It is Ruth.
舰长日志，星历3025.8
Captain's log, stardate 3025.8.
这颗星球越来越不同寻常，调查仍在继续
Investigation of this increasingly unusual planet continues,
我们见到了根本不可能存在的事物
and we are seeing things that cannot possibly exist.
可他们看起来却如此真实
Yet they are undeniably real.
麦考伊，你能听见我吗？
McCoy, do you read me?
露丝
Ruth.
露丝，怎么可能是你？
Ruth, how can it be you?
你怎么可能在这里？
How can you possibly be here?
你还是如此年轻
You haven't aged.
都过去15年了
It's been 15 years.
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
什么都不重要
None of that matters.
- 我是寇克 - 找到苏鲁了吗，舰长？
- Kirk here. - Did you find Mr. Sulu, captain?
- 什么？ - 苏鲁找到了吗？
- What? - Did you find Mr. Sulu?
没有
No.
但我确定他没事
But I'm sure he's all right.
长官，你还好吧？
Sir, are you all right?
是的，我很好
Yes, I'm fine.
罗德里格斯请求和寇克船长通话
Rodriguez to Captain Kirk.
好的，罗德里格斯先生
Yes, Mr. Rodriguez.
舰长，我刚才见到…一群鸟
Captain, a while ago I saw, well, birds.
一大群鸟
A whole flock of them.
罗德里克斯，你不是喜欢鸟吗？
Don't you like birds, Mr. Rodriguez?
我的确喜欢，长官，可调查结果显示的却是…
I like them fine, sir, but all our surveys show--
那肯定是仪器出现了故障
Then offhand I'd say our instruments are defective.
这里的确存在生命形式
There are indeed life forms on this planet.
长官…
Sir...
我们的调查是不会有误的
...our surveys couldn't have been that wrong.
罗德里克斯先生…
Mr. Rodriguez...
让全体搜查人员在林中的空地集合
...have the search parties rendezvous at the glade.
我要把一切弄个水落石出
I'd like some answers to all of this.
- 遵命，长官 - 你要走吗？
- Aye, aye, sir. - You have to go?
我不想走
I don't want to.
如果你想，你还会再见到我
You'll see me again, if you want to.
你还没告诉我…
You haven't told me...
做你该做的事吧
Do what you have to do.
我会等你的
And I’ll be waiting.
露丝
Ruth.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长
- Kirk here. - Captain.
什么事，史波克？
Yes, Mr. Spock?
星球表面读数异常，舰长
I'm getting strange readings from the planet's surface, captain.
出现某种力场
Some sort of power field down there.
说具体些
Specify.
一种极为复杂的能量正不断增强，还在消耗我们的能量
A highly sophisticated type of energy draining our power and increasing.
我们的通信开始受到影响
Beginning to affect our communications.
能定位其来源吗？
Can you pinpoint the source?
估计来自星球的地下
Could be coming from beneath the planet's surface.
扫描图显示某种工业活动
Patterns would indicate some sort of industrial activity.
保持联络，史波克
Keep me posted, Mr. Spock.
我们会继续在这里调查
We'll continue our investigation down here.
通话完毕
Captain out.
- 感觉好点了吗？ - 好些了…
- Feeling better? - A little...
别让我一个人呆在这
...but I wouldn't want to be alone here.
为什么？这里那么美，虽然我承认这里是有点奇怪
Why not? This is a beautiful place. A little strange, I’ll admit.
没错，这里太美了
That's just it. It's almost too beautiful.
我的裙子被撕破前，我甚至还在想
Why, I was thinking, even before my tunic was torn,
在这种地方，一个女孩应该…
that in a place like this, a girl should be...
哦…让我想想…
Oh, let's see now...
一个女孩应该打扮得像童话里的公主
A girl should be dressed like a fairy-tale princess,
穿着飘逸的裙子，戴着有面纱的帽子
with lots of floaty stuff and a tall hat with a veil.
我懂你意思
I see what you mean.
到那时，唐璜的整个军队都会为你而战…
But then you'd have whole armies of Don Juans to fight off...
我也会
...and me too.
真的吗，大夫？
Is that a promise, doctor?
哦…医生，它们真漂亮
Oh, doctor, they're lovely.
瞧我，医生
Look at me, doctor.
一位需要呵护，值得为之而战的女子
A lady to be protected and fought for.
一位拥有王室血脉的公主
A princess of the blood royal.
这些还远远不够…
You are all of those things...
你风情万种
...and many more.
要是你穿上，会更美
They'll look even lovelier with you wearing them.
医生…
Doctor...
我担心
...I'm afraid.
没事，我不知道这是怎么回事
Now, look, I don't know how or why,
可衣服既然在这
but the dress is here.
我想看你穿上它
I'd like to see you in it.
何不把它穿上？
Why don't you put it on.
好吧
All right.
但你就呆在原地
But you stay right there.
不许偷看
And don't peek.
亲爱的姑娘，我可是个医生
My dear girl, I am a doctor.
我要是看，那也是我的本职
When I peek, it's in the line of duty.
呼叫麦考伊医生
Calling Dr. McCoy.
我是麦考伊
McCoy here.
我…
I...
我听不太清楚，是罗德里克斯吗？
I can't read you very well. Is this Rodriguez?
音量不能再大了
This is all the volume I can get on this thing.
我还是听不清
I can't read you well either.
舰长命令…
Captain's orders...
所有人在空地集合
...rendezvous at that glade where he first found you.
好的
Right.
到底怎么啦？
What the devil's wrong with...
通讯那么糟
...communications?
埃斯特班？
Esteban?
医生
Doctor.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy.
你是科学官，史波克，我需要你来解释一下
You're the science officer, Mr. Spock. I want some answers.
首先，麦考伊的“爱丽丝梦游仙境”
First it was McCoy's Alice in Wonderland,
遇到了不该遇到的动物
where there was supposedly no animal life.
然后是苏鲁的枪，之前并没有检测出煅造金属的存在
Then Sulu's gun, where there was no refined metal detected.
罗德里克斯口中的鸟群
Rodriguez's birds.
然后是我…
And then my...
遇到的两个熟人
Well, the two people I saw.
难道这些都是幻觉？
Any chance these could be hallucinations?
其中一个幻觉还在我下颚打了一记
One hallucination flattened me with a clout on the jaw.
另一个…
The other...
听上去很痛，跟真的似的
That sounds like a painful reality.
是啊
Yes.
一定有合理的解释
There must be some logical explanation.
你的信号很弱，能把音量调高些吗？
Your signal is very weak. Can you turn up your gain?
我已经调到最大了
I'm already on maximum.
舰长，要我送一支武装队下来吗？
Captain, shall I beam down an armed party?
不用，这里的人都装备了相位枪
Negative. Our people here are armed with phasers.
而且目前尚未遇到真正的…
Besides, there's yet to be any real...
危险
...danger.
通话结束
Captain out.
麦考伊，麦考伊，你能听见我吗？
McCoy. McCoy, do you read me?
寇克呼叫麦考伊
Kirk to McCoy. Come in.
舰长，快掩护
Captain. Take cover.
- 一个武士正在追我！ - 什么？
- There's a samurai after me! - A what?
我是说…有个…
I mean... There was...
舰长，你得相信我
Captain, you've gotta believe me.
我相信，我也遇到了有趣的人
I do. I've met some interesting personalities myself.
你见到其他登陆队员了吗？
Have you seen any of the others from the landing party?
几分钟前收到罗德里克斯的呼叫
Got a call a few minutes ago. Rodriguez.
说你要我们在空地集合
Said you were rendezvousing back at the glade.
我希望他能通知到大家
I hope he got through to everybody.
- 通信几乎瘫痪了 - 此外
- Communications are almost out. - That's not all.
- 我的相位枪也坏了 - 什么？
- So's my phaser. - What?
- 我们最好返回空地 - 是，长官
- We'd better get back to the glade. - Yes, sir.
看
Look.
有人从舰桥下来了
Someone beaming down from the bridge.
有东西在干扰传输
Trying to. Something's obstructing it.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
我命令任何人不许离开星舰
My orders were no one was to leave the ship.
有这个必要，舰长
Necessary, captain.
不能用通信器和你联络
Unable to contact you by communicator,
传送器现在也不能用了
and the transporter is useless to us now.
之前我说过，这里力场不同寻常
As I told you before, there's an unusual power field down here.
它正在吸食星舰的能量
It's soaking up all the energy at the source.
我计算了它的增长速度
I calculated the rate of its growth
发现只剩传送一个人的能量
and reasoned that I just might be able to transport one more person.
做得好，你能帮助我们
Good. We can use your help.
我们会被困在这里吗，舰长？
We're stranded down here, captain?
只有把一切弄个水落石出
Until we can find out what this is all about.
一个人都没有
There's no one here.
这就是舰长说的集合点
This is where the captain said to rendezvous.
我发誓我听见附近有人
I swear I heard someone moving around.
别瞎说
Don't talk like that.
公主是不会怕的
A princess shouldn't be afraid,
即使英勇的骑士不在身旁
not with a brave knight to protect her.
在那边
That way.
我们分头去找
Spread out. Let's find it.
这些东西不是真的
These things cannot be real.
幻象伤不了我们
And hallucinations can't harm us.
你退回去
Go back to where you were.
他死了
He's dead.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplemental.
和进取号的联系已完全中断
All contact with the Enterprise has been lost.
我们受困于此
We're trapped here.
星舰的医疗官，我的好朋友，死了
Our ship's surgeon, my personal friend, is dead.
现在我们肯定眼前的一切都是真的
We're certain now that whatever we're facing is terribly real.
这是我的错
It's my fault.
这一切本不该发生
It never would have happened.
- 我的错 - 不
- It's my fault. - No.
是我的错，都是我不好
It is, it is. I'm to blame.
文书
Yeoman.
我们有麻烦了
We're in trouble.
每个队员都要提高警惕，理智思考
I need every crewman alert and thinking.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长，舰长！
Captain. Captain!
你最好过来看看，长官
You'd better have a look at this, sir.
- 我不明白 - 我也不明白了，苏鲁
- I don't understand. - Neither do I, Mr. Sulu.
但在我们离开这颗星球之前，我会弄明白的
But before we leave this planet, I will.
这像个傀儡
It's like a dummy, captain.
它并无生命
It couldn't be alive.
- 三录仪器检测结果？ - 还在检测中
- Tricorder? - Still operating, sir.
史波克！
Mr. Spock!
你怎么看？
What do you make of that?
这不是人类皮肤的组织，舰长
This is not human skin tissue, captain.
更像蜂窝式结构
More closely resembles the cellular casting
我们用来修复伤口的
we use for wound repairs.
但更加精致
Much finer, of course.
我需要明确的判断，史波克
I want an exact judgement, Mr. Spock.
这无疑是一项医学发明
This is definitely a mechanical contrivance.
它和这里的植物有相同的细胞结构
It has the same basic cell structure as the plants here,
甚至是树木和草
even the trees, the grass.
你是说这是植物，史波克？
Are you saying that this is a plant, Mr. Spock?
我是说他们都有复合蜂窝式细胞结构
I'm saying that these are all multicellular castings.
这里的植物，动物，人
The plants, the animals, the people.
他们都是制造出来的
They're all being manufactured.
被谁？为什么？
By who? And why?
为什么恰恰又是这些东西？
And why these particular things?
唯一确定的是
All we know for certain
它们就跟真的一样
is that they act exactly like the real thing.
一样会喜悦…
Just as pleasant...
一样会死去
...or just as deadly.
那是什么？
What is it?
真是不可思议
Of all the crazy things.
记得我刚还和你说
Remember what I was telling you a little while ago
过去的战争和当时摸样可笑的飞机
about the early wars and the funny air-vehicles they used?
那就是其中的一架
That's one of them.
它会伤害我们吗？
Can it hurt us?
除非它进行低空扫射
Not unless it makes a strafing run.
什么？
A what?
就是它们袭击地面的方式
The way they used to attack people on the ground.
快跑！
Come on!
安吉拉
Angela.
舰长！
Captain!
- 麦考伊的尸体 - 不见了，被拖走了
- McCoy's body. - He's gone. He's been dragged off.
黑骑士也一样
The Black Knight too.
- 史波克？ - 我此刻分析
- Spock? - At this point, captain, my analysis
或许不那么科学
may not sound very scientific.
麦考伊的死是个科学事实
McCoy's death is a scientific fact.
有一种可能，尽管可能性很小…
There is one slight possibility, very slim, but nevertheless...
舰长，在你遇到那两个人之前
Captain, what were your thoughts just before
你在想什么？
you encountered the people you described?
我在…
I was...
我在回想上学的时光
I was thinking about the Academy.
我那时…
My days...
嘿，小吉姆，我见到你把援兵带来了
Hey, Jim baby. I see you brought up reinforcements.
我正等你呢，小吉米
Well, I’m waiting for you, Jimmy boy.
芬尼根
Finnegan.
Finnegan!
我的船员怎么了？
What's been happening to my people?
带上苏鲁，去找麦考伊的尸体
Take Sulu, find McCoy's body.
我来对付这个人
This man is my problem.
- 舰长，等等 - 这是命令，史波克
- Captain, wait. - That's an order, Mr. Spock.
我在这！
Here I am!
跑呀！
Run!
吉姆
Jim.
来找我呀！
Find me!
看见我了吗？
Can't you see me?
来抓我呀！
Come and get me!
我在这！
Here I am!
来呀！
Come on!
你永远都摸不着头脑！
You never could find your head with both hands!
还像过去那样，小吉米！
Like it used to be, Jimmy!
你还记得吗？
Remember?
嘿，吉姆
Hey, Jim.
我有几个问题
I want some answers.
上来呀
Well, coming up.
起来
Get up.
起来，起来
Get up. Get up.
你一直都光明正大，不是吗？
Always fight fair, don't you?
就像个长官和绅士
You officer and gentleman, you.
你这个愚蠢的低年级学生
You stupid underclassman.
我还年轻，依然20多岁
I've got the edge. I'm still 20 years old.
看看你
Look at you.
你已经老了
You're an old man.
我…我的腿动不了了
I-- I can't move me legs.
我的腿没知觉了
I can't feel me legs.
我的腰断了，我的背被你打折了
My back is broken. You've broken me back.
来吧，有感觉吗？
Here, can you feel that?
现在有感觉吗？
Can you feel that, now?
好好睡一觉，小吉米
Sleep sweet, Jimmy boy.
尽情地睡吧
Sleep as long as you like.
永远地睡吧，小吉姆，不要醒来
Sleep forever, Jim baby. Forever and forever.
你怎么还是不明白，小吉米？
Won't you ever learn, Jim boy?
你永远也赢不了我
You never could take me, no.
芬尼根
Finnegan.
就一件事
One thing.
好吧，说吧
Sure. Name it.
事情的真相
Answers.
靠你自己找
Earn them.
还不赖
Not bad.
对过去的偿还吗，吉姆？
Kind of makes up for things, huh, Jim?
要还的太多
A lot of things.
我的船员怎么了？
What's been happening to my people?
我从不回答新生的问题，小吉米
I never answer questions from plebes, Jimmy boy.
我不是新生
I'm not a plebe.
如今都过了15年了
This is today, 1 5 years later.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我正是你期望的产物，小吉米
I'm being exactly what you expect me to be, Jimmy boy.
你过得愉快吗，舰长？
Did you enjoy it, captain?
是的，我很愉快
Yes, I enjoyed it.
这么多年以后…
After all these years...
我确实很愉快
I did enjoy it.
这是我多年之后一直想做的事
The one thing I wanted to do after all these years
把芬尼根打个屁滚尿流
was beat the tar out of Finnegan.
这正支持了我得出的那条理论
Which supports a theory I've been formulating.
只要是我们想到的人和事物
We're all meeting people and things
都会在这里出现
that we happen to be thinking about at the moment.
是的，我们的想法能被感知
Yes, somehow our thoughts are read,
这些东西被快速制造出来，并提供给我们
these things are quickly manufactured and provided for us.
若碰巧在想危险的…
Dangerous if we happen to be thinking about--
- 是的，我们必须控制自己的思绪 - 好难
- Yes, we must control our thoughts. - Difficult.
我们碰到的力场显然来自地下
The force field we encountered is obviously underground,
这些东西做好后，从通道送至地面
manufacturing these things. Passages lead to the surface.
就像罗德里克斯
As, for example, when Rodriguez
- 想老虎… - 史波克！
- thought of a tiger-- - Spock!
我们必须找到登陆队，警告他们
We've gotta get back to the landing party, warn them.
苏鲁，罗德里克斯，巴罗斯
Sulu, Rodriguez, Barrows.
- 过来集合 - 长官…
- Front and centre. - Sir--
不要提问，这是命令
Don't ask any questions, that's an order.
所有人立正
Brace front, everyone.
别交谈，屏住气，别思考
Don't talk, don't breathe, don't think.
立正
You're at attention.
集中精力立正…
Concentrate on that...
别开小差
...and only that.
集中精力
Concentrate.
舰长
Captain.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是这儿的管家，寇克舰长
I am the caretaker of this place, Captain Kirk.
- 你知道我的名字？ - 当然
- You know my name? - But of course.
罗德里克斯上尉，苏鲁上尉…
Lieutenant Rodriguez, Lieutenant Sulu...
…巴罗斯文书和史波克先生
...Yeoman Barrows and Mr. Spock.
我们发现你们对这儿还不了解
We have only just discovered that you do not understand all this.
这些经历本是为了取悦你们
These experiences were intended to amuse you.
取悦？
Amuse?
这就是你的解释？
That's your word for what we've been through?
这些经历都只是暂时的
But none of this is permanent.
你们只用去想自己最大的愿望
Here you have to only imagine your fondest wishes,
过去希望实现的，或是新的愿望，什么都行
either old ones which you wish to relive or new ones, anything at all.
打斗，恐惧，爱情，胜利
Battle, fear, love, triumph.
任何能让你开心的事都会发生
Anything that pleases you can be made to happen.
- 就像“游乐园” - 没错
- The term is "amusement park." - Of course.
地球上用的一个古老的词，在那里
An old Earth name for a place where people could go
人们可以体验各种奇妙的事
to see and do all sorts of fascinating things.
这颗星球是为我们的族人而建，供他们游玩的
This entire planet was constructed for our race of people, to come and play.
游玩？
Play?
你们进化得那么高级，还需要游玩？
As advanced as you obviously are, and you still play?
是的，游玩，苏鲁先生
Yes, play, Mr. Sulu.
大脑结构越复杂
The more complex the mind,
越需要简单的游乐方式
the greater the need for the simplicity of play.
正是，舰长，你悟性真高
Exactly, captain. How very perceptive of you.
这还是无法解释我医疗官的死亡
That still doesn't explain the death of my ship's surgeon.
也许压根就没死，吉姆
Possibly because no one has died, Jim.
我被带到地下“疗养”，效果显著
I was taken below the surface for some rather remarkable repairs.
真不可思议
It's amazing.
下面有座规模宏大的工厂，令人难以置信
They've got a factory complex down there you wouldn't believe.
他们能迅速制造出任何事物
They can build or do anything, immediately.
她们你又如何解释？
And how do you explain them?
她们…我…
Them. Well, l...
我想到自己在参宿七II看过的表演
I was thinking about a little cabaret I know on Rigel II,
她俩当时就在合唱队里
and there were these two girls in the chorus line there.
接着…她们就出现了
And, well, here they are.
毕竟，我还在休假
Well, after all, I am on shore leave.
我也是
And so am I.
是的，你也是
Yes, so you are.
姑娘们，我想你们得到别处去了
Well, girls, I suppose you can turn something up.
很抱歉给你们带来的不便
We regret that some of you've been made uncomfortable.
这些都是你们制造的？你们是谁？
You say your people built all this? Who are you?
从哪颗星球来？
What planet are you from?
据我所知，你们人类还没做好理解我们的准备
My impression is that your race is not yet ready to understand us, captain.
我同意
I tend to agree.
- 我是寇克 - 舰桥呼叫舰长
- Kirk here. - This is the bridge, captain.
我们的能量系统已恢复正常
Our power systems have just come back in.
需要支援吗？
Do you require assistance?
不，一切都在掌控中，上尉，待命
No, everything is in order, lieutenant. Stand by.
- 然而… - 是，长官
- However... - Aye, aye, sir.
只要你们小心得当
...if you would use the proper caution,
我们这颗星球会是个理想的游乐场
this amusement planet of ours could be an ideal place for
能让你们好好放松，如果你愿意的话
your people to enjoy themselves, if you wish.
医生批准啦，吉姆
It's what the doctor ordered, Jim.
- 上尉 - 长官？
- Lieutenant. - Sir?
开始传送登陆休假队
Commence transporting shore-leave parties.
让他们准备好，这将是最棒的一次登陆休假
Tell them to prepare for the best shore leave they've ever had.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
舰长，我得回去照看星舰
Captain, I'll go back aboard ship and take over.
这位年轻的女士，非常抱歉…
With all due respects to the young lady...
我这个假休得够长了
...I've already had as much shore leave as I care for.
不，史波克，我回去，你…
No, Mr. Spock. I’ll go, you--
还是算了…
On the other hand...
我还是留下…待一两天
I'll stay...for a day or two.
你们过得愉快吗，先生们？
Did you enjoy your rest, gentlemen?
是的，史波克，我们过得很愉快
Yes, we did, Mr. Spock. I think we did.
的确很愉快，史波克
Indeed we did, Mr. Spock.
真不合逻辑
Most illogical.
曲速一前进，苏鲁
Ahead warp factor 1, Mr. Sulu.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/